各位考生请注意。五分钟后将播送2022年武汉市初中毕业生学业考试英语试卷听力部分。
Exclusive Exclusive
各位考。生请注意，三分钟后将播送二零二二年武汉市初中毕业生学业考试英语试卷听力部分。
各位考生请注意，一分钟后将播送二零二二年武汉市初中毕业生学业考试英语试卷听力部分。
Exclusive Exclusive Where are you going?
现在是试音时间。
To the library.
试音到此结束。现在播送二零二二年武汉市初中毕业生学业考试英语试卷听力部分。该部分分为第一、第二。和第三节。注意，做题时先将答案画在试卷上。该部分录音内容结束后，你将有两分钟的时间将你的答案转涂到英语答题卡上。第一节，听下面四个问题，每个问题后有三个答语，从题中所给的三个选项中选出最佳选项。听完每。每个问题后，你都有五秒钟的时间来作答和阅读下一小题。每个问题仅读一遍。
Text 1 How often do you go to the library?
Text 2 When was the spring school trip?
Text 3 What do you want for your birthday?
Text 4 Where were the robots made?
第一节到此结束。第二节，听下面八段对话。每段对话后有一个小题，从题中所给的三个选项中选出最佳选项。听完每段对话后，你都有十秒钟的时间来作答有关小题和阅读下一小题。每段对话仅读一遍。
Text 5 Steve, don't stick your chopsticks into your bow.
It's impolite. Oh, sorry.
I won't. Text Excuse me,
can you tell me where I can buy some medicine?
Yes, there's a supermarket in the shopping center.
Text 7 What do you like about that movie?
The happy ending, of course, and the acting was fascinating.
Text 8 Your son Jerry is making excellent progress.
that so? you for letting me know, Mr.
Brown. It's hard to tell at home, you know.
Text 9 Hello, I'm calling to sign up for the art course.
Sorry, there are no more spaces available.
So many students like it.
Text 10 Susan, how's business coming along?
It's beginning to pick up.
I believe everything will go well soon.
Text 11 Dad, what does that road sign mean?
It means there will be bears walking across the road in about three kilometers.
Text 12 Tom, how was the horse riding yesterday?
Not so bad, but my horse was too polite.
When we came to offense, he stopped and let me go first.
第二节到此结束。第三节：听下面四段对话或独白，每段对话或独白后有几个小题，从题中所给的三个选项中选出最佳选项。听每段。对话或独白前，你将有时间阅读各个小题，每小题五秒钟。听完后，各小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。每段对话或独白读两遍。听下面一段对话，回答十三至十五三个小题。
Text 13 Hi, Mandy, how's your new school?
It's great, but I have to take the school bus every morning.
Well, at least you don't have to take the train anymore.
But the bus comes at 6.30 a.m.
I have to get up at 5.45 and leave home in 30 minutes, or I will miss the bus.
Wow, that's early.
What about clothes?
Do students have to wear uniforms?
Yes, we do, and they look nice.
Cool, what about lunch?
We can eat either at school or outside.
Great, how's your school lunch?
It's tasty, but I hate waiting in a long line.
Hi, Mandy, how's your new school?
It's great, but I have to take the school bus every morning.
Well, at least you don't have to take the train anymore.
But the bus comes at 6.30 a.m.
I have to get up at 5.45 and leave home in 30 minutes, or I will miss the bus.
Wow, that's early.
What about clothes?
Do students have to wear uniforms?
Yes, we do, and they look nice.
Cool, what about lunch?
We can eat either at school or outside.
Great, how's your school lunch?
It's tasty, but I hate waiting in a long line.
听下面一段对话，回答十六至十八三个小题。
It's great to see you again, Jeff.
Have you been in the city long?
You too, Emma.
I've been here for about a week.
Okay, have you been to the amusement park yet?
It's not far away.
Yeah, there are so many people in the park.
Well, how about shopping?
I know a great store.
I'm not interested in it, you know.
Then how about visiting the space center?
Actually, I've already been there and met a real astronaut.
That's amazing. Wow, you've done a lot.
Well, is there anything you want to do?
You know, I just want to stay at the hotel today.
Anyway, thanks for your kind offer.
It's great to see you again, Jeff.
Have you been in the city long?
You too, Emma.
I've been here for about a week.
Okay, have you been to the amusement park yet?
It's not far away.
Yeah, there are so many people in the park.
Well, how about shopping?
I know a great store.
I'm not interested in it, you know.
Then how about visiting the space center?
Actually, I've already been there and met a real astronaut.
That's amazing. Wow, you've done a lot.
Well, is there anything you want to do?
You know, I just want to stay at the hotel today.
Anyway, thanks for your kind offer.
听下面一段对话，回答十。九至二十二四个小题。
Thanks for offer.
Text 15 Happy birthday, Yanyan.
Here's your gift.
Oh, you remembered.
What a surprise!
You can open it.
I don't think I should open it now.
In China, we open a gift later.
But back in my country, we open a gift right now.
So what do I do?
You needn't wait.
Okay. Oh, it's a dictionary.
Thank you. I really wanted one.
I'm happy you like it.
And I noticed another difference.
You accept a gift with both hands.
But in the West, we usually don't pay much attention to that.
Yes, that's one of Chinese traditions.
We were taught to be polite in that way at a very young age.
Good. I'm interested in all Chinese traditions.
Would you tell me more?
There are a lot.
For example, during Spring Festival,
we carefully prepare for the New Year's Eve dinner.
And we also hand up red lanterns.
Another popular custom is paying a New Year's visit.
That's interesting.
Happy birthday, Yanyan.
Here's your gift.
Oh, you remembered.
What a surprise.
You can open it.
I don't think I should open it now.
In China, we open a gift later.
But back in my country, we open a gift right now.
So what do I do?
You needn't wait.
Okay. Oh, it's a dictionary.
Thank you. I really wanted one.
I'm happy you like it.
And I noticed another difference.
You accept a gift with both hands.
But in the West, we usually don't pay much attention to that.
Yes, that's one of Chinese traditions.
We were taught to be polite in that way at a very young age.
Good. I'm interested in all Chinese traditions.
Would you tell me more?
There are a lot.
For example, during Spring Festival, we carefully prepare for the New Year's Eve
dinner. And we also hand up red lanterns.
Another popular custom is paying a New Year's visit.
That's interesting.
听下面一段独白，回答二十三至二十五三个小题。
Text 16 Work with us in our rainforest conservation project.
You will live deep in the Amazon rainforest at our camp,
and you will take part in important research.
This is the chance of a lifetime to work and live in one of the most beautiful and
exciting places on the planet.
You will help study the wild animals, help the full -time staff, and clean the camp.
You do not need experience for this job.
You just need to be hardworking and full of energy.
You need to have a strong personality.
Our volunteers work for six hours a day, and there is no Internet or electricity
here. The nearest town is four hours away by boat.
If you would like to join us on our work program, call 435 -7689 for more
information. Text with us in our rainforest conservation project.
You will live deep in the Amazon rainforest at our camp, and you will take part in
important research. This is the chance of a lifetime to work and live in one of the
beautiful and exciting places on the planet.
You will help study the wild animals, help the full -time staff, and clean the camp.
You do not need experience for this job.
You just need to be hardworking and full of energy.
You need to have a strong personality.
Our volunteers work for six hours a day, and there is no Internet or electricity
here. The nearest town is four hours away by boat.
If you would like to join us on our work program, call 435 -7689 for more
information. Thank you for watching.
第三节到此结束。现在你有两分钟的时间，将答案转涂到英语答题卡上。
Thank you. Thank you.
听力测试到此结束。